María Camila **Ángel Flórez**

SYSTEMS AND COMPUTING ENGINEER · INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER

Carrera 5 78-82 Bogotá, Colombia

□ (+57) 316 522 1679 | ■ mc.angel182@gmail.com | ♠ mcangel182.github.io | □ mcangel182 | □ mcangel182

Summary _____

Recent graduate from Universidad de los Andes, with degrees in Systems and Computing Engineering and Industrial Engineering. Experience as Teaching Assistant in five software development-related courses at Universidad de los Andes, as well as software engineer in two internships undertaken both in academic and industrial environments. Solid academic performance, strong work ethics and willingness to learn. Mobile programming experience in Android, iOS and Cordova. Front-end programming experience in JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery and AngularJS. Back-end programming experience in Java, Python, PHP and Ruby on Rails.

Education _

Systems and Computing Engineering

Bogotá, Colombia Aug. 2011 - Oct. 2017

Universidad de los Andes

• **Cumulative GPA**: 4.71/5.0

• Thesis: Conception and development of web application to store and visualize medical images.

Industrial Engineering

Bogotá, Colombia

Universidad de los Andes

Aug. 2011 - Oct. 2017

• Cumulative GPA: 4.71/5.0

• Thesis: Two-phase algorithms for the vehicle routing problem with scarce, reusable resources in the cattle industry.

Experience _

CREATIS - Internship

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Sep. 2015 - Jul. 2016

- Implemented a web application to store and visualize medical data and images using a PHP based open source platform.
- Developed two visualization modules to render stacks of 2D Dicom images and 3D Nifti volumes, using Cornerstone and Brainbrowser.
- Implemented a patient search module using Solr as search engine.

Bizagi - Internship

Bogotá, Colombia

JUNIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Jan. 2015 - Jul. 2015

- Developed new features for the latest version release of Bizagi Studio and the desktop and mobile versions of Bizagi's Work Portal.
- Fixed bugs found by the QA team in previous versions of the software.

Universidad de los Andes - Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Bogotá, Colombia

COURSES: ALGORITHMS AND OBJECT ORIENTATED PROGRAMMING I AND II, DATA STRUCTURES, TRANSACTIONAL

Systems, and Mobile App Development

2012 - 2014, Jan. 2017 - Jun. 2017

- Helped students in the development of several tasks during lab sessions.
- Assessed exams and assignments giving feedback to the students on their mistakes.
- Researched for APIs, libraries and tools to be used in projects assigned to students.
- Created Android programming guides aimed at introducing students to different concepts, features, best practices and tools of Android app development.

Conference Participation

II Congreso Colombiano de Investigación Operativa - ASOCIO 2017

Medellín, Colombia

PRESENTER

Aug. 2017

- Angel, M.C., Paris, L., Alvarez, D. and Gomez, C. A heuristic approach for the vehicle routing problem with scarce, reusable resources.
- Paris, L., **Angel, M.C.**, Alvarez, D. and Gomez, C. *Two-phase hybrid algorithm for the vehicle routing problem with scarce, reusable resources*

Amsterdam, Netherlands

PRESENTER Jul. 2017

• Angel, M.C., Paris, L., Alvarez, D. and Gomez, C. A heuristic approach for the vehicle routing problem with scarce, reusable resources.

• Paris, L., Angel, M.C., Alvarez, D. and Gomez, C. Two-phase hybrid algorithm for the vehicle routing problem with scarce, reusable resources.

Honors & Awards

Candidate for the Summa Cum Laude degree in Systems and Computing Engineering

(awaiting results), awarded to those students whose cumulative GPA is in the top 1% of the 2017 the graduates of their faculty during the last 5 years, and who demonstrate integral merits, in a interview before the committee appointed by the Academic Council.

Bogotá, Colombia

Candidate for the Summa Cum Laude degree in Industrial Engineering (awaiting results),

awarded to those students whose cumulative GPA is in the top 1% of the the graduates of their 2017 faculty during the last 5 years, and who demonstrate integral merits, in a interview before the committee appointed by the Academic Council.

Bogotá, Colombia

The Anglo Colombian School Award for "First Place in Form", awarded to those students 2005 - 2011 who obtain the highest cumulative GPA in their form.

Bogotá, Colombia

Skills _

Language

• Spanish: Native language

- English: Bilingual proficiencyFrench: Limited working proficiency
- Languages: Java, Swift, Java Script, HTML, CSS, Python, PHP and Ruby.
- Database: Oracle and MySQL.

Programming

- Tools: AndroidStudio, Xcode, Eclipse, WebStorm, Visual Studio and RubyMine.
- Operating Systems: Android, iOS, Mac OS X, Microsoft Windows and Fedora (Linux).

Interests _

Knitting: Member of the Colectivo de Tejido Maria Cano Vive.

Dancing: Passionate about salsa dancing.

Cinema: Cinephile interested in independent and international cinema.